<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Brian Foshee</title>
  <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/</id>
  <updated>2019-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2019 Brian Foshee</rights>
  <subtitle>Hi. I&#39;m Brian Foshee. I write software.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/feeds/atom" rel="self"></link>
  <author>
    <name>Brian Foshee</name>
    <email>brian@brianfoshee.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Europe In 60 Seconds</title>
    <updated>2019-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/europe-in-60-seconds</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to Europe for 4 months in 2018 as part of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;year off&lt;/a&gt;. While I was&#xA;there I shot a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/px&#34;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; and videos, the latter of which I&amp;rsquo;m&#xA;finally going through. My summary of the whole trip is now up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Wr4ysHaOJo&#34;&gt;on my YouTube&#xA;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/europe-in-60-seconds" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Video summary of my 4 month trip through Europe in 2018.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>30</title>
    <updated>2018-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/turning-30</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I turned 28 it occured to me for the first time that 30 was about to&#xA;happen. The thought of that stressed me out for a minute. Had I done everything&#xA;I needed to do in my 20s? Was I ready for whatever being in my 30s means? Am I&#xA;getting old?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My 20s were, taken as a whole, great. Sure, I had some difficult years, but I&#xA;pushed through a lot of internal struggles, I figured out and became confident&#xA;in who I am, I realized what my priorities currently are in life, I learned from&#xA;many failures and successes, I made the best group of friends who support me and&#xA;hold me accountable, and I built a solid career foundation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After giving it more thought, I realized that turning 30 would give me a chance to&#xA;focus in on what&amp;rsquo;s important to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And 30 isn&amp;rsquo;t old.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I became content with turning 30. Excited, even. And then I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/why-im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;take an&#xA;entire year off&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that my 30s begin strong and that I have the&#xA;time to reflect on where I&amp;rsquo;ve been, take the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from my&#xA;journey so far, and set myself on a path to make the first few years of my 30s&#xA;fruitful (I would say all of my 30s but I have a hard time planning more than a&#xA;few years ahead, if I can even decide what to do tomorrow or next week.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My 20s were more or less doing the &amp;lsquo;usual&amp;rsquo;: go to college, figure out a career,&#xA;figure out how to be an adult and on my own. Thirty is a blank canvas to paint,&#xA;a new chapter to write, new problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is my 30th birthday. I&amp;rsquo;m spending it on the beautiful island of Kefalonia,&#xA;Greece, on a secluded beach, under the sun, looking out at the blue and green&#xA;water that you can see right through. Which is exactly where I wanted to be&#xA;today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve given myself a giant birthday present in this trip around Europe and this&#xA;year off in general. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more pleased with the decision.  Who knows&#xA;what the next few years will look like, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited about what I&amp;rsquo;ve taken&#xA;away from the thinking and reflecting that I&amp;rsquo;ve done during the last six months&#xA;of not working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/turning-30" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Today is my 30th birthday.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grandmama Sara</title>
    <updated>2018-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/grandmama-sara</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This summer I got to spend time with Grandmama right before Grandaddy passed&#xA;away and before I left for Europe. For a while we sat on the covered porch where&#xA;she lived because she wanted to be outside. Not much was said, but the memories&#xA;I have of her were present and that was enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grandmama Sara’s Summer Camp - the one week every summer that she wrangled her 9&#xA;grandchildren together - provided so many experiences that contributed to making&#xA;me who I am (including my sweet tooth - she never said no to us eating candy or&#xA;drinking bottomless Yoo-hoos).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each summer she showed us her world, where she lived and worked and grew up, the&#xA;people she knew, and people she didn&amp;rsquo;t know but could somehow talk into letting&#xA;her bring a rowdy group of cousins to their factory/business/etc to learn&#xA;something new. She taught us about family, work, and responsibility. She seemed&#xA;to have an endless amount of energy to deal with us, and never missed scratching&#xA;our backs and singing us a song before we fell asleep each night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grandmama went to be with Grandaddy today. I’m thankful for all of the time&#xA;I had with them, I’m sad they’re gone and I&amp;rsquo;ll miss them both dearly, but I know&#xA;they’ll continue to cheer us on from wherever they are. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I originally &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BpH79UggV2z/?taken-by=brianfoshee&#34;&gt;posted this text on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, but wanted to preserve it&#xA;here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/grandmama-sara" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Grandmama left us to be with Grandaddy today</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Went Off-Grid For One Week</title>
    <updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/one-week-off-grid</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last 10 years I have worked and played on a computer for 8+ hours a day,&#xA;leaving little room for much else while not always accomplishing anything. My&#xA;cellphone became something I would reach for first thing in the morning, in the&#xA;middle of the night if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep, or when I had any idle moment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I began my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/why-im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;year off&lt;/a&gt; by spending one week away from these devices that I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;become so accustomed to using all day, every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While my year off is a reboot of my lifestyle, my week off-grid was a reboot of&#xA;my use of technology. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/about&#34;&gt;make a living off of technology&lt;/a&gt;, but the&#xA;always-available nature of the internet allowed me to get into unhealthy usage&#xA;habits like checking email multiple times a day, reading websites that haven&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;changed in the five minutes since I last read them, or taking my phone out of my&#xA;pocket to fill time that would be better spent interacting with the people&#xA;around me or reading a book or writing or reflecting on the moment. Backing away&#xA;from screens would hopefully allow me to be more present and focused.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the night before I began this week off-grid, I powered off my laptop and my&#xA;cellphone. For 7 days they sat on my dresser, unused. I also did not watch any&#xA;TV during this time. Instead I planned to read, write, walk, and be outside. My&#xA;parents were around for 5 of the 7 days, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in complete isolation, and&#xA;they were nice enough to not turn on the TV or talk about current events. I also&#xA;told some close friends about my plans so they knew what I was up to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the week unfolded I felt more focused when doing one thing at a time. I spent&#xA;a lot of time sitting outside and thinking about nothing. It was so refreshing.&#xA;My head was clear. I stopped reaching for my phone that wasn&amp;rsquo;t there. I was&#xA;enjoying being disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I journaled each night before going to bed. I was at a lake house so I strung&#xA;up my hammock on the dock for a reading/thinking/napping spot. The background&#xA;noise of birds chirping, water flowing, boats passing, and the occasional rain&#xA;storm on the metal roof set a relaxing mood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When my parents and I went to a friend&amp;rsquo;s graduation party, I felt much more&#xA;engaged with those around me. Even when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t talking to anyone I could sit&#xA;with my own thoughts and be happy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took 4 days until I had a strong urge to get my phone out and look things up.&#xA;Luckily that day I had some house work to do to keep me active.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the end of the week neared, I felt like I was getting what I wanted from the&#xA;experience. I also started to miss my friends! The wonderful thing about the&#xA;internet is how connected we can be to the people we love no matter how far away&#xA;they are. It&amp;rsquo;s no substitute for connecting in-person, but as I travel around I&#xA;enjoy being able to talk to my family and friends from wherever I am. It makes&#xA;them seem a little closer even though I&amp;rsquo;m (currently) an ocean away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no escaping the fact that I need my computer and the internet to write&#xA;software and make a living. I love making things - software or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog&#34;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt; or&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCnxocnbh74guQll8yqWGUA&#34;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/px&#34;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; - and my computer is the tool that usually helps me&#xA;with that. I also enjoy seeing what others have created or learning something&#xA;new, often on social media or around the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also no denying the utility of a smartphone. I can navigate around a&#xA;foreign city, pay my credit card bill, transfer money into my checking account&#xA;when I need to use an ATM, and send my travel partner my half of a dinner bill,&#xA;all from a device that fits in my pocket. I can also endlessly scroll through&#xA;Instagram and Twitter, check and re-check the same websites, and feel a&#xA;compulsion to talk to people through that device instead of enjoying whatever&#xA;moment I am experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by stripping out all of the excess and unnecessary usage of my phone&#xA;and computer I can re-learn to use them only for necessary utility and for&#xA;creating. And when I don&amp;rsquo;t need to do either I can choose to do something else&#xA;like read or be active or meet someone new or do nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am I perfectly cured of my bad technology habits? No. But going off-grid for a&#xA;week made me more aware of them and one by one I&amp;rsquo;m working to change them. I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;removed all social media apps from my phone, in favor of logging into&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/brianfoshee/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brianfoshee&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCnxocnbh74guQll8yqWGUA&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop. This helps me to&#xA;limit my usage to once a day or less, and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to take my&#xA;phone out nearly as much. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to keep myself from unnecessarily&#xA;checking websites throughout the day, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use the web browser only&#xA;when I really need to look up travel info.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I find that it&amp;rsquo;s important to learn how to slow down, and to make sure that the&#xA;things I&amp;rsquo;m doing are important to me instead of them being habit or &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s how&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s always been done.&amp;rdquo; Going off-grid gave me a clear head to see what my&#xA;priorities are, and in the time since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on clearing out&#xA;what&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will absolutely go off-grid again, and likely will do it at least once more&#xA;during this year off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/one-week-off-grid" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">I turned off my computer and phone for a week to reboot my technology habits.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I&#39;m Taking a Year Off</title>
    <updated>2018-09-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/why-im-taking-a-year-off</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written various forms of this post as journal entries over the last 18&#xA;months. The first was 17 January 2017 (yes, 2017) when I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have decided to take a one year sabbatical beginning 1 June 2018. The timing&#xA;is such that it&amp;rsquo;ll take place during the last 6 months of my 20s and the first 6&#xA;months of my 30s. This will signify in many ways a transition into my 30s and&#xA;will set my pace of life for the following few years. I don&amp;rsquo;t yet have an idea&#xA;as to exactly what I&amp;rsquo;ll do on this break, but I do know that I&amp;rsquo;d like to take&#xA;the time to refocus my life and make sure I&amp;rsquo;m living every aspect of it as I&#xA;want to instead of how I think other people think I should.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My decision to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;take a year off&lt;/a&gt; was gut instinct. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to&#xA;trust my gut instinct because it&amp;rsquo;s usually right, no matter how difficult it may&#xA;be to accept or act on what needs to be done. I remember the feeling of making&#xA;this particular decision. It was refreshing - powerful, almost - to be able to&#xA;step out of the norm of my life and get back to where my heart has been for a&#xA;while. And being four months into it now, I can say that it was the right&#xA;decision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to take some sort of break since my final two years of college (I&#xA;was there for six years). I worked all through college, first as an intern at an&#xA;architectural testing firm and then writing software for a startup, and was&#xA;burnt out. I wanted to do nothing for a few months. To recharge. But I hadn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;saved up enough money to be able to do that so I pushed through and put the&#xA;idea on the back burner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years after I graduated from college I hit a low point, and through&#xA;that did a lot of growing up and learning about life. I made career and&#xA;financial goals to work towards in the second half of my 20s. I met those goals&#xA;and did things that I had no idea were possible back when I made them, but I&#xA;felt like something was missing. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really taken care of myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I spent the whole of my 20s investing in and building my career, I didn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;do much to invest in myself personally. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking care of my mind and body&#xA;and spirit as much as I should have been. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m in a position to cash in&#xA;on my career investments and get a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of work weeks to myself, I am&#xA;making me a priority.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;m doing the things that make me happy, push me out of my comfort&#xA;zone, make me active, and get me ready for my 30s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/why-im-taking-a-year-off" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Throughout my 20s I mostly focused on my career; I&#39;m taking a year off to focus on myself.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Iceland 2018</title>
    <updated>2018-09-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/iceland-2018</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first stop on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;year-off&lt;/a&gt; travels was Iceland! I went with two&#xA;friends and former roommates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/keepupwithnicostar/&#34;&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/merjench/&#34;&gt;Merjen&lt;/a&gt;. We were there for&#xA;5 days, 11 August through 16 August, and spent our time exploring the south&#xA;coast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the photo galleries I posted:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/px/iceland-year-off&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; - Days 1 and 2. From Reykjavik to Hella, then to Vik.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/px/iceland-2018-part-2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; - Day 3. From Vik to Hof then back to Selfoss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/px/iceland-2018-part-3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; - Days 4 and 5. Grindavik and Reykjavik.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/iceland-2018" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">I visited the south coast of Iceland in August of 2018.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Terrible Weekend On The Lake</title>
    <updated>2018-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/a-terrible-weekend-on-the-lake</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A quick preface/disclaimer/warning: I put this post together from a few of my&#xA;journal entries. They were written in near real-time while I was experiencing&#xA;the death of a man who I didn&amp;rsquo;t know. He died near my family&amp;rsquo;s lake house last&#xA;weekend, where I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending this summer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Saturday, 9 June 2018&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saturday started out like any other day. I woke up around 9:30A.M., took a&#xA;shower, ate breakfast, and read in my hammock on the dock. After eating a late&#xA;lunch I went back down to the dock to shave my head. When I got there I noticed&#xA;a massive storm sitting over the lake to the north and west. It began thundering&#xA;so I went back up to the house. My brother Price and I started planning his&#xA;bachelor weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sky darkened with clouds as the storm made its way south. The wind picked up&#xA;and was blowing off the lake, towards our house. There were whitecaps on the lake&#xA;and our windows rattled with a few gusts of wind. Waves were breaking onto the dock.&#xA;Lightning was flashing on the far side of the lake. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t raining.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Price and I looked out the windows and noticed that two boats - a pontoon boat&#xA;and a speedboat - were meeting a pair of kayakers out on the lake, maybe 100&#xA;yards off our dock. The pontoon boat floated between us and the kayaks, blocking&#xA;our view of them. This was all far enough away that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t see what was&#xA;going on, so Price got our binoculars. I could see people on the boats, and the&#xA;two kayaks were vertical and mostly underwater. The boats were floating north&#xA;and neither seemed to have their engine turned on. But nobody was trying to get&#xA;the kayaks. Or the paddles. There were life jackets in the water. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;anybody else on the lake. Something seemed off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Price walked down to our dock when the boats floated out of eyesight (some of&#xA;our trees block the view to the north, so we couldn&amp;rsquo;t see anything after the&#xA;boats floated past our neighbor&amp;rsquo;s dock.) Melinda, our neighbor to the south,&#xA;walked over to meet him. After a minute or two I heard sirens. As I walked down&#xA;to the dock, Price was running up to the road to meet the firetruck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I got to the dock Melinda looked very concerned. She told me that she&#xA;thought someone went under. That took me a second to process, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;any time to think on it because the two boats were driving towards our dock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The speedboat arrived first, on the north side of our dock. On board was a&#xA;woman, her brother, and three children. The man helped to keep the boat from&#xA;slamming into the dock, as the wind and waves had not calmed down. I helped the&#xA;three kids and the woman off the boat. I took down my hammock so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in&#xA;the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pontoon boat arrived next with two young couples and a woman on board. Price&#xA;helped tie it up to the front of the dock. The woman got off first, crying and&#xA;in shock. Another woman got off and looked at me with the widest eyes, a look&#xA;that I won&amp;rsquo;t soon forget.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first woman was met by an EMT who walked her to an ambulance. She and her&#xA;husband had fallen off their kayaks and into the water. Her husband drowned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this point the firefighters had arrived on our dock. One of them got in the&#xA;speedboat to go back out to where the man drowned. An ambulance was parked in&#xA;Melinda&amp;rsquo;s driveway. Police officers arrived in plain clothes because they had&#xA;all been enjoying the weekend and were not on duty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slowly more and more emergency personnel showed up. The Sheriff. His lieutenant&#xA;and deputies. More firefighters. More officers. They took our statements. Price&#xA;and I put folding chairs out for the two couples who were in the pontoon boat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two kayakers had been out on the lake for the day. They were on the far side of&#xA;the lake when the storm began rolling in. They decided to make their way to the&#xA;other side of the lake - where our house is, and near where they had put the&#xA;kayaks in - which is almost a mile across. Neither had a life jacket on, and&#xA;neither knew how to swim well. They were panicking and paddling hard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They flagged down two boats when they were about 3/4s of the way across. A wave&#xA;knocked him out of his kayak. He grabbed her kayak, flipping her out. The people&#xA;in the pontoon boat threw all of their life jackets towards him. He wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put&#xA;one on. He was panicking. They got her onto the boat. When they went back to get&#xA;him he was gone. This all happened in the moments before Price and I looked&#xA;through binoculars to see the kayaks vertical in the water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The emergency personnel cleared everyone off our dock. Sheriff Hancock asked&#xA;Price and I if they could use our dock and our yard and we said of course. The&#xA;dive team showed up and used the pontoon boat, which was a rental. Boats from&#xA;the Department of Natural Resources were gridding the search area with sonar.&#xA;Off-duty police officers who were on their personal fishing boats joined in the&#xA;search.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I walked up to the house to calm down and drink some water. I started writing.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re currently still searching. It&amp;rsquo;s 7:09 PM. He went under at probably&#xA;4:00P.M.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A light rain began.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met Mercedes. She was in the speedboat. I helped her and the three kids off&#xA;when they got to our dock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met Zach, he went kayaking with him three weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met her cousin. She was thankful we let the family sit on our porch, which was&#xA;out of eyesight of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.walb.com/story/38391166/missing-kayakers-body-found&#34;&gt;local media&lt;/a&gt; who had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Police tape was strung across our yard and into Melinda&amp;rsquo;s yard, on the side of&#xA;our house facing the road. The Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s Command Center RV was parked in our&#xA;driveway. The dive team&amp;rsquo;s pickup truck was parked in our yard by the dock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The young couples that were on the pontoon boat were brought back to the marina&#xA;where they rented it from to get their car. We&amp;rsquo;ve since only spoken to them via&#xA;text message.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dive team packed up after sunset, around 9P.M. They’ll be back at 6:30A.M.&#xA;Price and I walked down to our dock, which was quiet except for the boats still&#xA;gridding nearby. Two police officers were there. They told us at least one will&#xA;be there all night. The rental pontoon boat was tied up to the end of our dock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well that night. I was mostly up thinking through too many what-if&#xA;scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sunday, 10 June 2018&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Price and I went for a walk, maybe around 10A.M. When we were out we heard and&#xA;then saw a helicopter flying up and down the shoreline of the lake and then back&#xA;to the search area off our dock. It was the Georgia State Patrol, who were&#xA;called in to assist in the search. We were out for about an hour. On our way&#xA;back in we could see the enormity of the recovery effort. In addition to the&#xA;Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s Command Center, there were at least five other vehicles in our front&#xA;yard and another five down by our dock. A fire truck was parked on the street.&#xA;Across the street were at least ten vehicles. A few media vehicles were parked&#xA;along the street. A tent was setup near the Command Center with food and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met Jason, his brother. He arrived late at night and slept in his car in&#xA;our driveway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t fully processed the situation, so instead of sitting inside I walked&#xA;over to Melinda&amp;rsquo;s to talk to her and her husband, Eddy. I watched the&#xA;helicopter flying directly overhead. I watched the boats on the water, the&#xA;divers in the water, the people all over our dock and our yard. I met a county&#xA;commissioner and some folks from the Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s office who I talked with for a&#xA;while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A cadaver dog arrived and went out on a boat. I’m not sure how that works but I&#xA;believe it&amp;rsquo;s trained to bark if it smells a human. Since there were other&#xA;boaters out on the lake the dog&amp;rsquo;s senses were thrown off and it was barking&#xA;quite a bit. The dog was biting at the water that went past the boat, which is&#xA;something our family dog used to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent four or five hours on Eddy and Melinda&amp;rsquo;s dock. The Sheriff came over to&#xA;chat at one point. It was after 9P.M. when they called off the search for the&#xA;day. Price and I went back up to the house, and to take our minds off things we&#xA;watched a Tig Notaro standup on Netflix. I barely made it through without&#xA;falling asleep. I slept like a rock that night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Monday, 11 June 2018&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Monday morning around 8A.M. Price and I were sitting on the porch swing. The&#xA;emergency personnel were just getting started for the day. The helicopter was&#xA;circling the lake when the pilot spotted him floating. We watched the boats -&#xA;two pontoon boats for the divers, a few DNR boats - all converge very quickly.&#xA;Sheriff Hancock walked up towards us and, giving a thumbs-up, told us they&amp;rsquo;d&#xA;found him. He walked Jason to a neighbor&amp;rsquo;s dock where the wife and other family&#xA;were waiting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The helicopter landed in a nearby yard. The boats slowly made their way back&#xA;towards our dock. Holding on to the front of one of the pontoon boats were two&#xA;divers in the water. They were holding onto an orange bag. The coroner showed up&#xA;and backed his truck to the steps that lead down to our dock. The divers carried&#xA;him out of the water and onto our dock, then up to the coroner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The divers packed and cleaned our dock. The coroner drove away. The Sheriff&#xA;walked up and thanked us for the use of our yard and dock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In no more than an hour the pickup trucks and the SUVs were gone. The&#xA;Sheriff&amp;rsquo;s Command Center RV was gone. The police tape was taken down. The family&#xA;left. The boats drove away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Price and I walked down to our dock for the first time since Saturday. We moved&#xA;the fenders back to the side of the dock. I put my hammock back up and laid in&#xA;it for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The man was a body builder. He was around 6&amp;rsquo;5&amp;rdquo; 250lbs, all muscle. It took less&#xA;than a minute for him to go under. There was nothing Price and I, or anyone&#xA;else, could have done. The people on the two boats that met them did everything&#xA;they could have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on the water, please have a life jacket available - one that is fitted&#xA;to your body size. Learn to swim. Learn to tread water. Learn to float.&#xA;Understand how quickly this could happen to even the strongest person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later in the week Price and I were in Florida to celebrate our niece&amp;rsquo;s sixth&#xA;birthday. We went out on a friend&amp;rsquo;s boat with six kids and three other adults.&#xA;It was our first time on the water since this whole experience. The kids all had&#xA;life jackets on, and there were enough on the boat for the adults. I found&#xA;myself double checking, even though I&amp;rsquo;d been out on this boat with these people&#xA;before and it probably hadn&amp;rsquo;t crossed my mind. Having grown up around boats and&#xA;on the water, these things are second-nature to me. We had a lovely time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The water will always be a part of my life. It makes me happy and calm. I feel&#xA;most relaxed and peaceful when I&amp;rsquo;m swimming or sailing or on a beach. Last&#xA;weekend I was reminded of the power of water. I&amp;rsquo;ll never take it for granted&#xA;again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/a-terrible-weekend-on-the-lake" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">A man drowned near my family&#39;s lake house and I was there to experience the event and the recovery effort.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I&#39;m Taking a Year Off</title>
    <updated>2018-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/im-taking-a-year-off</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day at The New York Times. Working here for the last two years&#xA;has been the most incredible experience of my career up to this point. I have&#xA;learned so much, I have grown as a person and as an engineer, and I have worked&#xA;with the best damn team that I could have asked for. I will miss you all&#xA;greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I get to start an adventure that I have wanted to go on for many years.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve waited for this, preparing financially and professionally for the day that&#xA;I would feel comfortable leaving a steady income and jumping into a big unknown.&#xA;I will be traveling for most of the year with few concrete plans, which is&#xA;exciting and scary and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along I will be posting regular updated here and on my&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/brianfoshee/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCnxocnbh74guQll8yqWGUA&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; accounts!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edit: I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/why-im-taking-a-year-off&#34;&gt;why I&amp;rsquo;m taking this year off&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/im-taking-a-year-off" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">I left my job writing software at The New York Times to travel for a year.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 10 - Flying Home</title>
    <updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/last-day-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day 10 of the trip was the last day we were in Japan. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/YRIYokhl6cc&#34;&gt;watch the video&#xA;on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our Airbnb hosts had a lovely breakfast prepared for us when we woke up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James had to leave super early that morning, but Nicole, Paul, and I decided to&#xA;go into Tokyo one last time to see the Imperial Palace and eat lunch. The palace&#xA;was closed but we got to walk around the grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then got on the Narita Express train to take us to the airport. I said&#xA;goodbye to Nicole (who I would see the next day because we&amp;rsquo;re roommates) and&#xA;Paul and headed to Terminal 2 for my flight back to NYC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the final video of the Japan 2017 Series! Look forward to a lot more&#xA;travel content to come later this summer, as I&amp;rsquo;m leaving my job this week to&#xA;start a new adventure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/last-day-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">Day 10 of the trip was the last day we were in Japan.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 9 - Chiba</title>
    <updated>2018-04-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/chiba-tokyo-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On day 9 of the trip we headed back near Tokyo for our last night in Japan. You&#xA;can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5bHAjetOe3E&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our bullet train left Osaka Station at 1:43PM and we arrived in Tokyo around&#xA;5PM. We then headed to our Airbnb in Chiba, which is on the north side of Tokyo&#xA;and closer to Narita Airport, which we&amp;rsquo;d all be going to the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The house we stayed in was a lovely traditional Japanese home where a family of&#xA;three lived. The mother and daughter were learning English together, and one of&#xA;the ways they practiced was by giving guests a tour of their house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We headed out to find dinner, but on a week night this far outside of Tokyo most&#xA;places were closing early. We ended up in a mall that was eerily empty but had&#xA;some snack food to try out. For dinner we of course chose the place that spoke&#xA;zero english, and google translate wasn&amp;rsquo;t much help. The meal ended up being&#xA;really good though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we walked in the rain to an American bar which was run by a&#xA;Japanese-speaking Persian man. At the bar we watched the movie Bartender&#xA;starring Tom Cruise, and enjoyed our last night in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/last-day-japan&#34;&gt;day ten of the trip&lt;/a&gt;: we leave our Airbnb and head into Tokyo one last&#xA;time, before making our way to the airport to fly home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/chiba-tokyo-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On day 9 of the trip we headed back near Tokyo for our last night in Japan.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 8 - Eating Okonomiyaki in Osaka</title>
    <updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/ferris-wheel-okonomiyaki-osaka-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On day 8 we travelled to Osaka, where we ate the most delicious meal of the trip&#xA;and also rode on a ferris wheel. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/tgniqOzwgHg&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube&#xA;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left at 11A.M. to head to Kyoto Station. Our Japan Rail train left at noon,&#xA;and the trip to Osaka was about 30 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After arriving we made our way to our Airbnb, then Nicole and I went out to get&#xA;massages. We had to make appointments for later in the day, so we wandered&#xA;around a pet store in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all then met at a restaurant for dinner. We chose a place that served&#xA;okonomiyaki, which is a grilled pancake / omelette from heaven. The restaurant&#xA;had a map where customers could pin where they were from.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After dinner we went to ride on a ferris wheel!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brandi then left for Thailand, so we said goodbye to her and then went back to&#xA;our Airbnb to do laundry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/chiba-tokyo-japan&#34;&gt;day nine of the trip&lt;/a&gt;: we take yet another train ride, and stay with a&#xA;family for our final night in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/ferris-wheel-okonomiyaki-osaka-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On day 8 we travelled to Osaka and ate okonomiyaki.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 7 - Part 2: Shrines in Kyoto</title>
    <updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/kiyomizu-dera-fushimi-inari-shrines-kyoto-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the second half of day seven we visited two shrines in Kyoto. You can&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/-qooMfJXTLU&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before getting to the shrines, Nicole and I went in search of an afternoon meal.&#xA;Most restaurants close between 2 and 5P.M., so all we could find was a cafe that&#xA;had some alright spaghetti.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first shrine, Kiyomizu-dera, was under renovation so we could only see part&#xA;of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the the buses were packed on account of it being tourist season, so we&#xA;decided to take a taxi to the next shrine. That shrine, Fushimi-inari, is famous&#xA;for having thousands of gates winding through trails in the woods. The cicada&#xA;bugs were really loud here too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we tried to get into a fancy restaurant but it required reservations,&#xA;so nicole and I split off to get tacos while Brandi, James, and Paul went to eat&#xA;at a hotpot restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/ferris-wheel-okonomiyaki-osaka-japan&#34;&gt;day eight of the trip&lt;/a&gt;: we eat okonomiyaki in Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/kiyomizu-dera-fushimi-inari-shrines-kyoto-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">During the second half of day seven we visited two shrines in Kyoto.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How We Built The New York Times Holiday Gift Guide</title>
    <updated>2018-04-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/building-the-new-york-times-holiday-gift-guide</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My team at The New York Times built the 2017 Holiday Gift Guide on the same&#xA;platform that we build &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/spotlight/guides&#34;&gt;How To Guides&lt;/a&gt;. It took effort from product,&#xA;design, editorial, and engineering, and you can read about how we did it &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.nytimes.com/how-we-made-the-holiday-gift-guide-72886d02b958&#34;&gt;on the&#xA;Times Open blog&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote the fun section titled &amp;ldquo;API and Data Model&#xA;Updates&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/building-the-new-york-times-holiday-gift-guide" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">My team at The New York Times built the 2017 Holiday Gift Guide on the same platform that we build How To Guides.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 7 - Part 1: Nishiki Market, Kyoto</title>
    <updated>2018-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/nishiki-market-kyoto-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We began day seven of the trip eating street food at Nishiki Market in Kyoto.&#xA;All of us tried some interesting food, and we wandered around the little shops&#xA;in the market as well. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/nRMu-3clHCY&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nicole tried a fried octopus ball and did not enjoy it. Paul was very&#xA;adventurous and tried just about everything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we&amp;rsquo;d had our fill we all got ice cream or slushies then went back to our&#xA;Airbnb to take naps around 2. When we woke up we were hungry for a full meal but&#xA;unfortunately most restaurants close at 2 and open again at 5. Nicole and I went&#xA;to find a cafe that might be open. We found a place that had some okay spaghetti&#xA;which held us over for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/kiyomizu-dera-fushimi-inari-shrines-kyoto-japan&#34;&gt;the second half of the day&lt;/a&gt; we visited a couple of shrines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/nishiki-market-kyoto-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">We began day seven of the trip eating street food at Nishiki Market in Kyoto.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 6 - Hiking (near) Mount Fuji</title>
    <updated>2018-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/hiking-mount-fuji-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On day six of the trip we hiked to a waterfall near mount fuji and then traveled&#xA;to Kyoto. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/J_1qWqCgVxs&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We woke up at 4:15A.M. to watch the sunrise, because we were told that it is the&#xA;best time to see Mount Fuji before the clouds roll in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After eating breakfast, we packed our bags and left them in the front office of&#xA;our villa. We needed to store them for a few hours while we went on a hike to a&#xA;local shrine and waterfall. The shrine was a 15 minute walk from our villa, and&#xA;the waterfall was a 30 minute hike from there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After cooling down at the waterfall, we decided to walk down the road that led&#xA;back to where we started instead of taking the trail down. We also met a solo&#xA;traveler from Luxembourg who hung out with us for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we got down to the road we were pretty hungry so we found a place to eat&#xA;lunch. We were told to try the local Yoshida Udon Noodle which is only available&#xA;in this area. It did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then got caught in a downpour, so our villa was nice enough to send a van to&#xA;pick us up and take us to the bus stop so we could make our way to Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 3:20P.M. bus ride was about 45 minutes long, and took us to Mishima station&#xA;where we got on a bullet train. This bullet train ride would be our first on the&#xA;trip. The train ride was a couple of hours long, and we got to Kyoto around&#xA;8P.M.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/nishiki-market-kyoto-japan&#34;&gt;day seven of the trip&lt;/a&gt;: we eat street food at an outdoor market in&#xA;Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/hiking-mount-fuji-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On day six of the trip we hiked to a waterfall near mount fuji and then traveled to Kyoto.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 5 - Leaving Tokyo</title>
    <updated>2018-03-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/leaving-tokyo-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On day five of our trip we leave Tokyo and travel to Mount Fuji! You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/II3IYlsGllo&#34;&gt;watch&#xA;the video on my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.  It took us most of the day, and a few&#xA;trains, to get there, but the views of the countryside were worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get out of Tokyo, we first took the local subway to Shinjuku station, where&#xA;we got on a Japan Rail train at 1:30PM. This train took us about an hour outside&#xA;of the city to Otsuki station.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once we arrived at Otsuki station, we waited for our 3:15PM train towards&#xA;Kawaguchiko station. This trip took about an hour as well, and we made many&#xA;local stops while passing through smaller towns along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Kawaguchiko station, a van from our hotel was waiting to pick us up. When we&#xA;got in the van, we were informed that we were being taken to a supermarket, and&#xA;that we had 30 minutes to buy groceries for dinner and breakfast. Apparently,&#xA;the few restaurants that were nearby closed early and opened late. The&#xA;supermarket was a godsend because they had real peanut butter!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we unpacked everything at our villa, we walked across the street to Lake&#xA;Kawaguchiko. Typically the clouds part after sunset, unveiling Mount Fuji, so we&#xA;waited by the lake and took in the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We got back to our villa after dark and made dinner. I believe it was some sort&#xA;of burrito / stir-fry hybrid. We also found out that we&amp;rsquo;d accidentally bought&#xA;alcohol-free beer. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After dinner we played cards, then went to the hot spring baths at our hotel.&#xA;There were separate rooms for men and women, and we had to get naked and take a&#xA;shower before getting in. Apparently the water was directly from the lake, and&#xA;meant to have healing powers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/hiking-mount-fuji-japan&#34;&gt;day six of the trip&lt;/a&gt;: we hike to a waterfall, we leave Mount Fuji, and&#xA;we ride on our first bullet train!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/leaving-tokyo-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On day five of our trip we leave Tokyo and travel to Mount Fuji!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 4 - Tokyo SkyTree</title>
    <updated>2018-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/tokyo-skytree-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the fourth day of the trip I met up with my cousin who was also in Japan, and&#xA;we went to Tokyo Skytree. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/z0569hrmPpQ&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube&#xA;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Day four was our last full day in Tokyo. We took it easy since the next morning&#xA;we were leaving for Mt Fuji. My cousin Lauren and I met up and spent part of the&#xA;day together. She wanted to check out Shibuya Crossing so we went back there. We&#xA;then got lost trying to find the sushi restaurant the rest of the group was at,&#xA;but eventually made it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We spent the afternoon wandering around the Imperial Palace (which was closed)&#xA;and running into a popup Oktoberfest, before heading to the Tokyo SkyTree Tower&#xA;to get a birds eye view of the city at night. Tokyo SkyTree was pretty neat, and&#xA;showed how huge a city Tokyo is. I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to check that view out during&#xA;the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After saying goodbye to Lauren, I headed back to the house. Unfortunately I&#xA;didn&amp;rsquo;t get any video, but we then went to a local bar for a couple of hours. We&#xA;had a very fun conversation with the bartender and another guy there, using&#xA;their bit of english, James&amp;rsquo; bit of Japanese, and a lot of assistance from&#xA;Google Translate. It was a great evening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/leaving-tokyo-japan&#34;&gt;day five of the trip&lt;/a&gt;, we leave Tokyo and make our way to Mt. Fuji!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/tokyo-skytree-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On the fourth day of the trip I met up with my cousin who was also in Japan, and we went to Tokyo Skytree.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 3 - Shinjuku, Shibuya, Sumida</title>
    <updated>2018-03-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/shinjuku-shibuya-sumida-tokyo-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On our third day in Tokyo we attend the Shinjuku Eisa Matsuri Festival, walk&#xA;around the Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden, walk through Shibuya Crossing, and&#xA;see the Sumida River Fireworks. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/mczzVb9uYI4&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube&#xA;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 8AM today, so I got a lot of sleep. I was still laying in bed&#xA;at 9:15AM, and everyone else is pretty tired as well. We have two festivals to&#xA;go to today so we are taking it easy this morning. We left around noon to go&#xA;towards the Shinjuku festival. We hung around there for an hour or so watching&#xA;the drum and dance performances. It was possibly the hottest day of the trip,&#xA;and incredibly humid, so we only lasted so long in the crowds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To cool off we headed to the Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden. I bought a lemonade&#xA;for 350 yen and we got in for 200 yen. We walked around for an hour or so,&#xA;before heading to Shibuya Crossing, one of the busiest intersections in the&#xA;world. We stopped in the Starbucks that has a view of the crossing from above so&#xA;we could take some video. There&amp;rsquo;s a timelapse in the video I linked at the&#xA;beginning of this post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon some rain set in so we went to find some food. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize&#xA;how long it&amp;rsquo;d been since I&amp;rsquo;d last eaten so I was getting a little out of it and&#xA;rather hangry. We found a nice place though and the noodles and shrimp hit the&#xA;spot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Newly energized, we walked to the Sumida River Fireworks Festival. Sort of. We&#xA;walked down a street next to the park the fireworks were at because there were&#xA;so many people. There was zero standing room, and the police were making sure&#xA;nobody stood in the street so we had to keep walking. It also was raining on us.&#xA;When we left we had to walk past one subway station because there was a mob of&#xA;people trying to get into it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We went to Ropongi Hills for dinner. Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s a really expensive area so&#xA;we went to a German place. I got a beer and pesto German noodles with smoked&#xA;salmon. We headed home around 11PM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/tokyo-skytree-japan&#34;&gt;day four of the trip&lt;/a&gt; I meet up with my cousin and we check out Tokyo&#xA;SkyTree.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/shinjuku-shibuya-sumida-tokyo-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On our third day in Tokyo we attend the Shinjuku Eisa Matsuri Festival, walk around the Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden, walk through Shibuya Crossing, and see the Sumida River Fireworks.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 2 - Akihabara, Tokyo</title>
    <updated>2018-02-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/akihabara-tokyo-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the second day of the trip we explored Akihabara, Tokyo, The Miraikan Science&#xA;Museum, and Rainbow Bridge. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/2dHKidesfeA&#34;&gt;watch the video on my YouTube&#xA;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left around 10AM to make our way towards Akihabara. Our first&#xA;stop was a giant 6 story arcade. It was loud, smelled like cigarettes (smoking&#xA;is still allowed indoors in Japan), and dark because there weren&amp;rsquo;t any windows.&#xA;We walked through all of the floors, and some of the group tried out a game or&#xA;two.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After wandering around some more we ended up at a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maid_café&#34;&gt;Maid Cafe&lt;/a&gt;. It&#xA;wasn&amp;rsquo;t lunch time yet so I had a waffle with ice cream. They didn&amp;rsquo;t allow&#xA;filming so we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get video or pictures. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite understand the Maid&#xA;Cafe thing, but James and Paul went back later in the trip and had more&#xA;authentic experience. Our next stop was the Don Quixote, a multi-story&#xA;Walmart-type store that has tiny aisles and anything you could need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d had our fix of the area, so we took a driverless monorail over&#xA;a bridge and to The Miraikan Science Museum. On our way over we saw people&#xA;dressed up in Mario character costumes driving go-karts down the street. At the&#xA;museum we saw a demo of Asimo, Honda&amp;rsquo;s robot that can walk, kick a ball, and hop&#xA;on one leg, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we left the museum we saw that we were near a BMW driving&#xA;experience course so we stopped to watch people drive cars around cones. It&#xA;seemed rather lame, or the drivers were timid. From there we walked to a mall to&#xA;sit inside and relax because it was really hot and humid outside.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After spending an hour or two at the mall we regrouped and made our&#xA;way to Rainbow Bridge. When we got there it wasn&amp;rsquo;t lit up, and an internet&#xA;search told us that it only lights up during a certain time of year. We did,&#xA;however, sit on the beach and enjoy a nice view of the Tokyo skyline and a lot&#xA;of really colorful boats out on the water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this point it was way past dinner time so we went to a ramen&#xA;place then made our way home. I picked up some bananas at the supermarket across&#xA;the street from our house, dumped my camera card onto my computer, and went to&#xA;sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/shinjuku-shibuya-sumida-tokyo-japan&#34;&gt;day three of the trip&lt;/a&gt; we attend a couple of festivals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/akihabara-tokyo-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On the second day of the trip we explored Akihabara, Tokyo, The Miraikan Science Museum, and Rainbow Bridge.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Japan Day 1 - Ueno, Tokyo</title>
    <updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/ueno-tokyo-japan</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the first full day of the trip, James, Brandi, and I explored Ueno, Tokyo&#xA;while waiting for Nicole and Paul to arrive. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/zp5WOnUz89M&#34;&gt;watch the video on my&#xA;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After waking up at 5AM local time and being unable to fall back asleep, I put on&#xA;my eye mask and laid in bed for a couple of hours. After we all decided that&#xA;sleep wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to happen, we left our Airbnb around 9AM to head to the Ueno&#xA;Zoo. The train/subway ride was 30-45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ueno Zoo is in a massive park with a museum, a few shrines, some statues,&#xA;and the biggest standalone Starbucks I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. We primarily went to the&#xA;zoo to waste time while waiting on Nicole and Paul to arrive later in the day,&#xA;but we were also there to see the giant panda. Along with the panda we saw a&#xA;polar bear, tiger, elephants, birds, and gorillas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the zoo we wandered around the area for a bit, stopping by a shrine. We&#xA;then made our way to get lunch at Cocoichiban, a chain curry restaurant. I&#xA;ordered the vegetarian curry with spinach and eggplant, and a scrambled egg.&#xA;Spicy level 2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From there we walked to a nearby lotus pond that was at least 5 acres in size if&#xA;not larger. It had a floating dock which we could walk out onto that was&#xA;surrounded by lotuses. We spent some time there, still waiting on Nicole and&#xA;Paul to land, then headed to see Tokyo Dome City. On our way there we stopped by&#xA;another shrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tokyo Dome City was FULL of k-pop fans. I think there was a signing or something&#xA;to get ready for upcoming concerts, but people were lined up for autographs or&#xA;pictures in what looked like at least a two hour line. After spending an hour or&#xA;so people watching, we walked to Tokyo Station to meet Paul and Nicole!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We walked around some fountains near the Imperial Palace, then headed back to&#xA;our Airbnb to drop bags off. After hanging out for a bit we set out looking for&#xA;dinner. I was getting really tired at this point but was also hungry. It was&#xA;probably 6PM or 7PM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took us probably 30 minutes to find somewhere to eat. We passed another&#xA;shrine that we walked through, then landed at a local spot where they spoke zero&#xA;English. We used the Google Translate app to sorta read the menu but that didn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;work. Luckily the waiter knew salmon, tuna, octopus, and sashimi so we ordered&#xA;those roles and a sashimi plate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was fighting off falling asleep at this point, but we made it back to the apt.&#xA;I dumped the footage from that day onto my computer and then fell asleep&#xA;immediately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/akihabara-tokyo-japan&#34;&gt;day two of the trip&lt;/a&gt; we explore Akihabara and Rainbow Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
    <link href="https://www.brianfoshee.com/blog/ueno-tokyo-japan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">On the first full day of the trip, James, Brandi, and I explored Ueno, Tokyo while waiting for Nicole and Paul to arrive.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>